Charles Wu

UX Engineer

+1 647-767-6126

charleswu.ca

Summary

A versatile user-experience designer & developer. Adept in converting user needs into product requirements, with project analysis skills. Efficient at creating designs that translate into tangible results, through the means of prototypes, animation, and code.

Skills

UX: User Research, User Testing, Information Architecture Design, Wireframing,

Prototyping (Adobe CS, Sketch, Axure), Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)

Dev: HTML, CSS (SCSS, BEM), JS (React, Ember), Python, Git

Experience

UX Engineer

Highline Beta Jul 2018 - Jun 2019

• Designed, built, and shipped products for internal & external projects, using lean methodologies

- Researched, explored, and validated novel industry *problems* for new ventures
- Generated, synthesized, and validated solutions for the aforementioned problems

Sr UX Developer

CareerJSM

Sep 2016 - Apr 2018

- Audited and implemented code for accessibility, responsiveness, and localization compatibility
- Conducted user testing and interviews iteratively through each feature release
- Mentored team members and led the company in best UX practices

UX Developer

Dive Networks

Aug 2015 - Jul 2016

- Optimized content for web and TV mediums, factoring in content size, speed, and viewer distance
- Created user personas and use-cases to enhance functionality and usability for key audiences
- Hosted company UX training sessions to enhance product usability and accessibility
- Developed an automation script to detect visual differences

Education

Bachelors of Applied Science (BASc), University of Waterloo

2010 - 2015

Systems Design Engineering, Option in Management Science